In this daring heist, the only color that counts is green
Dead Presidents is a action, crime, drama film directed by Albert Hughes.
On the streets they call cash dead presidents.
And that's just what a Vietnam veteran is after when he returns home from
the war only to find himself drawn into a life of crime.
With the aid of his fellow vets he plans the ultimate heist -- a
daring robbery of an armored car filled with unmarked U.S.
Anthony Curtis, played by Larenz Tate.
Kirby, played by Keith David.
Skip, played by Chris Tucker.
Jose, played by Freddy Rodríguez.
Juanita Benson, played by Rose Jackson.
Deliah Benson, played by N'Bushe Wright.
Dead Presidents is a 1995 American crime film co-written,
produced and directed by the Hughes Brothers.
The film chronicles the life of Anthony Curtis (Larenz Tate), focusing on his teenage years as a
high school graduate and his experiences during the Vietnam War as a Recon Marine.
As he returns to his hometown in The Bronx, Curtis finds himself struggling to
support himself and his family, eventually turning to a life of crime.
Dead Presidents is based partly on the real-life experiences of Haywood T.
Kirkland (aka Ari S.
Merretazon), whose true story was detailed in the book Bloods: An Oral
History of the Vietnam War by Black Veterans  by Wallace Terry.
Certain characters from the film are based on real acquaintances of Kirkland,
who served time in prison after committing robbery in facepaint.
The film is also loosely based on several incidents involving the Black
Liberation Army, notably the Brink's armored truck robbery.
The film explores themes of vietnam, drug abuse, post-traumatic
stress disorder (ptsd), war veteran, redemption.
The tone is emotional and intense.